Stetson Reed

Saint George, UT - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Stetson-Reed/6815e11935b8a1f4

Commended by previous employers for being ambitious, teachable, and highly motivated. Areas of focus include learning new business processes, recognizing pain points, and implementing cost-effective solutions. Strong knowledge of Management Information Systems (MIS) and Business Intelligence (BI) software. Specialization in Reporting, Data Visualization, and Strategic Decision Making.

Certifications:

Salesforce Certified Administrator

· Software:

Salesforce | Pardot | Cognos | UltiPro | Canvas | Teamwork | iCIMS | SumTotal | GoToMeeting | GoToAssist | Join.me | Slack | Google AdWords & Analytics | Mailchimp | Hootesuite | Access | Excel | Project | Visio | WordPress | Intuit Quickbooks | Camtasia | Snagit | Illustrator | Photoshop | Tableau | Jaspersoft Studio

· Languages:

SQL | HTML | Apex | Visualforce | Java | Python Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

HR Manager

Holbrook Asphalt Co. - Saint George, UT - May 2017 to Present

Manager of Human Resources for 120-150 employees.

- Developed recruiting initiatives and conducted interviews. Made hiring decisions and initiated onboarding processes.
- Analyzed business processes and implemented solutions to increase efficiency, productivity, and lower costs.
- Developed processes to maintain compliance with Federal, State, OHSA, and DOT regulations.
- Researched and proposed HRIS and applicant tracking systems to replace outdated processes.
- Created performance and disciplinary programs.

Analyst | HR Technology and Reporting

SkyWest Airlines - Saint George, UT - August 2016 to May 2017

Simultaneously managed multiple large-scale initiatives including the implementation of Salesforce (Sales Cloud & Pardot), development of company recruitment processes, automation of employee separations, and adoption of SumTotal learning management system (LMS). Provided data visualization through adhoc reporting and dashboards using Business Intelligence and Human Resource Information Systems. Applications: Salesforce, Pardot, Cognos, UltiPro, iCIMS, Tableau, Jaspersoft Studio, Excel, Project, Visio, GoToAssist, Google AdWords, Apex, Visualforce, HTML, SQL

Results:

- Slashed potential legal penalties by \$28,000, and reduced required employee labor hours by 208 hrs/yr.
- Inflated marketing email open rate to 94.07% and email click-through rate to 45.75%.
- SQL reporting and analytics provided real-time insight to top-level executives for critical decisions.

Financial Analyst

Liahona Children's Foundation - December 2015 to November 2016

Completely overhauled an outdated internal financial reporting structure including policies and procedures for donations/fundraising, budgeting, approvals, expenditures, training, and reporting. Trained country supervisors

throughout 16 countries on use of new systems and reporting expenses. Applications: Slack, Access, Excel, Quickbooks

"Stetson did an excellent job helping to create and implement the Liahona Children's Foundation financial reporting structure. I gave him the project and he ran with it. This was a difficult project that was very murky on how to accomplish it. Stetson did a great job in coming up with ideas and then carrying out those ideas." - Scott Rasmussen, CFO

Substitute Teacher

Kelly Services - Saint George, UT - January 2016 to September 2016

Substitute Teacher with secondary education emphasis for the Washington County School District.

Business Development Analyst

St. George Museum of Science - Saint George, UT - January 2016 to August 2016

Managed multiple projects that lifted the museum from concept to reality. Designed, proposed, and implemented plans for Business Strategy, Corporate Identity/Branding, Website Creation, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), Market Research, Marketing Campaigns, Marketing Automation, Promotional Strategy, Exhibit Design, Incorporation, and 501(c)3 Status Filing. Applications: WordPress, Mailchimp, Hootesuite, Illustrator, Photoshop, HTML

Results:

- Established professional relationships with Washington County School District and the City of St. George leading to \$20,000 of additional funding and winning a contract for an after-school outreach program.
- Incorporated the museum, filed for IRS 501(c)3 status, established bank accounts, published by-laws and company policies, organized and facilitated executive board meetings, and organized a successful business plan.

Treasurer

Dixie State University - April 2015 to August 2016

Ensured positive account balances, prepared financial budgets, approved expenditures, maintained accurate financial records, reviewed financial reports, and oversaw booster and events committees. Applications: Canvas, TidBit

Advanced Sr. Plasma Center Technician

Baxter International Inc - July 2012 to January 2016

Responsible for basic phlebotomy and troubleshooting of plasmapherisis equipment, and ensured safety and quality through administration of employee health and safety (EHS) audit. Promoted to "Advanced Sr. Plasma Center Technician" and nominated for "Employee of the Year".

Leadership Development Instructor

National Youth Leadership Training (NYLT) - Saint George, UT - January 2008 to May 2010

Train youth on core leadership concepts as outlined in the NYLT course.

Vision, Goals, Planning

SMART Goals

Planning and Problem Solving Tools

Assessment Tools

Teaching EDGE

Stages of Team Development

Conflict Resolution

Valuing People

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Business Administration

Dixie State University
December 2017

Associate in General Science

Dixie State University - Saint George, UT May 2012

SKILLS

Consulting (3 years), Reporting (3 years), Salesforce (1 year), Cognos (1 year), SQL (1 year), Marketing Automation (1 year), Business Management (3 years), Business Analysis (3 years), Business Intelligence (1 year), Business Development (3 years), Sales Management (1 year), Sales (1 year), Project Management (3 years), Leadership Development (5 years), Operations Management (2 years), Performance Management (2 years), Human Resources (3 years), Hiring (3 years)

LINKS

http://linkedin.com/in/stetsonreed

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

Salesforce.com Certified Administrator

March 2017 to Present